[
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Genesis?",
        "answer": "A. God created all things and covenants with humanity to bring salvation.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-2</td><td>Creation</td></tr><tr><td>3-4</td><td>Fall and Cain</td></tr><tr><td>5-10</td><td>Noah</td></tr><tr><td>11</td><td>Tower of Babel</td></tr><tr><td>12-24</td><td>Abraham</td></tr><tr><td>25-26</td><td>Isaac</td></tr><tr><td>27-36</td><td>Jacob</td></tr><tr><td>37-50</td><td>Joseph</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Exodus?",
        "answer": "A. God delivers and establishes his covenant people.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-18</td><td>God’s Deliverance of Israel</td></tr><tr><td>19-24</td><td>God’s Covenant Law</td></tr><tr><td>25-40</td><td>God's Holy Dwelling</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Leviticus?",
        "answer": "A. God provides atonement so his covenant people may dwell with him.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-7</td><td>The Sacrifices the Lord Requires</td></tr><tr><td>8-10</td><td>The Priests the Lord Desires</td></tr><tr><td>11-15</td><td>Recognzing and Remedying Uncleanness</td></tr><tr><td>16</td><td>Day of Atonement</td></tr><tr><td>17-25</td><td>Living as a Holy Nation</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Deuteronomy?",
        "answer": "A. Second giving of the law.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-4</td><td>Historical Prologue</td></tr><tr><td>5-26</td><td>Restating the Law</td></tr><tr><td>27-30</td><td>Blessings and Curses</td></tr><tr><td>31-34</td><td>Transition to Joshua</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Joshua?",
        "answer": "A. Joshua leads Israel to conquer the promised land.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-5</td><td>Prologue & Entering the Promised Land</td></tr><tr><td>6-12</td><td>Taking the Promised Land</td></tr><tr><td>13-21</td><td>Dividing the Land</td></tr><tr><td>22-24</td><td>Serving the Lord in the Land</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Judges?",
        "answer": "A. Cycle of Israel sinning and God sending a judge.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-3:6</td><td>Roots of Israel’s Unfaithfulness</td></tr><tr><td>3:7-16:31</td><td>Deuteronomic Cycle: Major Judges</td></tr><tr><td>17-21</td><td>Depth of Israel’s Unfaithfulness</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Ruth?",
        "answer": "A. God is faithful to redeem.<br><br><table><tr><td>1</td><td>Tragedy & return to Bethlehem</td></tr><tr><td>2</td><td>Ruth meets Boaz</td></tr><tr><td>3</td><td>Naomi’s plan</td></tr><tr><td>4</td><td>Boaz Redeems Ruth</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Ezra?",
        "answer": "A. A remnant returns to restore the temple, and Ezra brings reforms.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-6</td><td>Return from Babylon Led by Zerubbabel</td></tr><tr><td>7-10</td><td>Return from Babylon Led by Ezra</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Nehemiah?",
        "answer": "A. Covenant renewal and rebuilding the wall and community.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-7</td><td>Rebuilding the Walls</td></tr><tr><td>8-10</td><td>Reading of the Law</td></tr><tr><td>11-13</td><td>Reforming the People</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Esther?",
        "answer": "A. God’s strange providence saves his people through a Jewish Queen in Persia.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-2</td><td>Crown – Esther’s Coronation</td></tr><tr><td>3-6</td><td>Conspiracy – Haman's Plot and Mordecai’s Rise to Power</td></tr><tr><td>7-8</td><td>Crash – Haman's Demise & the Jewish People's Deliverance</td></tr><tr><td>9-10</td><td>Celebration – Liberation and Celebration</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Job?",
        "answer": "A. Satan is subject to God’s authority and Job’s faith is tested.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-2</td><td>Prologue – Job’s test</td></tr><tr><td>3-31</td><td>Dialogue with friends (Eliphaz, Bildad, & Zophar)</td></tr><tr><td>32-37</td><td>Elihu’s speeches</td></tr><tr><td>38-42</td><td>God’s discourses & Job’s restoration</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Isaiah?",
        "answer": "A. Warning of future judgment and promise of a coming messiah.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-39</td><td>God Judges his Rebellious People</td></tr><tr><td>40-55</td><td>God Consoles his Exiled People</td></tr><tr><td>56-66</td><td>God Promises Salvation</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Jeremiah?",
        "answer": "A. Judgment through Babylonian captivity, and God makes a new covenant.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-25</td><td>Jeremiah’s Call and Warnings against Judah</td></tr><tr><td>26-45</td><td>Stories of Disaster with a Message of Hope</td></tr><tr><td>46-52</td><td>Warnings against the Nations</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Ezekiel?",
        "answer": "A. The exile of Judah because of their sin and promise of future restoration.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-24</td><td>Judgment Coming to Jerusalem</td></tr><tr><td>25-32</td><td>Judgment Coming to the Nations</td></tr><tr><td>33-48</td><td>Restoration of God's People</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Daniel?",
        "answer": "A. God’s protects Daniel in exile and prophecy of future history.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-6</td><td>Daniel’s Stories of God’s Sovereignty</td></tr><tr><td>7-12</td><td>Daniel’s Visions of God’s Sovereignty</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Hosea?",
        "answer": "A. Israel compared to an adulterous wife and God the faithful husband. (To Israel)<br><br><table><tr><td>1-3</td><td>Hosea's Marriage</td></tr><tr><td>4-10</td><td>Israel's unfaithfulness & judgment</td></tr><tr><td>11-14</td><td>God's faithfulness</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Jonah?",
        "answer": "A. God demonstrates mercy to wicked nation that repents. (To Israel)<br><br><table><tr><td>1</td><td>Fleeing from God's Mission</td></tr><tr><td>2</td><td>Jonah's Prayer of Repentance</td></tr><tr><td>3</td><td>Fulfilling God's Mission</td></tr><tr><td>4</td><td>Questioning God's Mercy</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Micah?",
        "answer": "A. Cylcles of judgment and restoration. (To Judah)<br><br><table><tr><td>1-2</td><td>Judgment of Samaria and Jerusalem</td></tr><tr><td>3-5</td><td>Judgment of Rulers and Prophets</td></tr><tr><td>6-7</td><td>Judgment of Israel and Final Restoration</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Nahum?",
        "answer": "A. Judgment against Nineveh. (To Judah)<br><br><table><tr><td>1</td><td>Yahweh as Divine Warior</td></tr><tr><td>2</td><td>Nineveh Judged</td></tr><tr><td>3</td><td>Woes against Nineveh</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Habakkuk?",
        "answer": "A. God promises everyone will be judged. (To Judah)<br><br><table><tr><td>1</td><td>Oracle against Judah</td></tr><tr><td>2</td><td>Oracle against Babylon</td></tr><tr><td>3</td><td>Habakkuk's Prayer</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Zephaniah?",
        "answer": "A. Announcement of the coming Day of the Lord for all nations. (To Judah)<br><br><table><tr><td>1</td><td>The Day of the Lord Will Come Against Judah</td></tr><tr><td>2</td><td>The Day of the Lord Will Come Against Judah's Enemies</td></tr><tr><td>3</td><td>The Day of the Lord Means Jugdment and Restoration</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Haggai?",
        "answer": "A. Encouraging Israel to rebuild the temple. (To Judah)<br><br><table><tr><td>1</td><td>Repent and Rebuild</td></tr><tr><td>2</td><td>The Lord gives Glory and Blessing</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Zechariah?",
        "answer": "A. Encouragement to Israel to finish rebuilding the temple. (To Judah)<br><br><table><tr><td>1-8</td><td>Zechariah’s 8 Visions</td></tr><tr><td>9-14</td><td>Zechariah’s 2 Oracles</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Malachi?",
        "answer": "A. Judgment in the coming Day of the Lord. (To Judah)<br><br><table><tr><td>1-4:3</td><td>Six Disputations</td></tr><tr><td>4:4-6</td><td>Prediction of the Day of the Lord</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Matthew?",
        "answer": "A. An account of Jesus’ life, death, and resurrection, focusing on Jesus’ role as the true king of the Jews.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-2</td><td>Birth Prologue</td></tr><tr><td>3-7</td><td>Coming of the Kingdom</td></tr><tr><td>8-10</td><td>Works of the Kingdom</td></tr><tr><td>11-13</td><td>Nature of the Kingdom</td></tr><tr><td>14-18</td><td>Authority of the Kingdom</td></tr><tr><td>19-25</td><td>Blessings and Judgments of the Kingdom</td></tr><tr><td>26-28</td><td>Passion and Resurrection</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Mark?",
        "answer": "A. Action packed account of Jesus’  ministry highlighting his authority and servanthood.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-8:26</td><td>Preaching the kingdom of God</td></tr><tr><td>8:27-10:52</td><td>Cost of the kingdom of God</td></tr><tr><td>11-16</td><td>Bringing in the Kingdom of God</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Luke?",
        "answer": "A. Chronological gospel based on eye-witness testimony emphasizing God’s plan including the Gentiles.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-4:13</td><td>John the Baptist and Jesus Parallels</td></tr><tr><td>4:14-9:50</td><td>Ministry in Galilee</td></tr><tr><td>9:51-19:27</td><td>Journey to Jerusalem</td></tr><tr><td>19:28-24:53</td><td>Triumphal Entry to Ascension</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of John?",
        "answer": "A. Theological account of Jesus’ ministry written for all to believe Jesus is the Christ, the Son of God.<br><br><table><tr><td>1:1-18</td><td>Prologue</td></tr><tr><td>1:19-12:50</td><td>\"Book of Signs\"</td></tr><tr><td>13-20</td><td>\"Book of the Passion\"</td></tr><tr><td>21</td><td>Epilogue</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Acts?",
        "answer": "A. Early church history focusing on the spread of the church after Christ’s ascension and Pentecost.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-7</td><td>The Church in Jerusalem</td></tr><tr><td>8-12</td><td>The Church in Judea, Samaria, and Antioch</td></tr><tr><td>13-14</td><td>First Missionary Journey of Paul</td></tr><tr><td>15</td><td>Jerusalem Council</td></tr><tr><td>16-18</td><td>Second Missionary Journey of Paul</td></tr><tr><td>19-21</td><td>Third Missionary Journey of Paul</td></tr><tr><td>22-28</td><td>From Jerusalem to Rome</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Romans?",
        "answer": "A. God’s plan of salvation and righteousness for all mankind.<br><br><table><tr><td>1:1-17</td><td>The Righteousness of God</td></tr><tr><td>1:18-3:20</td><td>The Lack of and Need for the Righteousness of God</td></tr><tr><td>3:21-8:39</td><td>The Gift of the Righteousness of God</td></tr><tr><td>9-11</td><td>A Challenge to the Righteousness of God</td></tr><tr><td>12-16</td><td>The Moral Demands of the Rightouesness of God</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of 1 Corinthians?",
        "answer": "A. Disciplinary letter with instruction and correction about various problems.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-4</td><td>Greeting & First Set of Problems: Divisions and Factions</td></tr><tr><td>5-7</td><td>Second Set of Problems: Sexual Integrity</td></tr><tr><td>8-10</td><td>Third Set of Problems: Food Offered to Idols</td></tr><tr><td>11-14</td><td>Fourth Set of Problems: Public Worship in the Church</td></tr><tr><td>15</td><td>Fifth Set of Problems: Resurrection</td></tr><tr><td>16</td><td>Closing</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of 2 Corinthians?",
        "answer": "A. Refuting false teachers who challenged Paul’s apostolic authority.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-7</td><td>Paul’s Defense of His Apostolic Ministry: A Historical Account</td></tr><tr><td>8-9</td><td>The Gentile Church’s Offering</td></tr><tr><td>10-13</td><td>Pau’s Defense of His Apostolic Ministry: Response to \"Super-apostles\"</td></tr><tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Galatians?",
        "answer": "A. Do not add circumcision to justification by faith alone.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-2</td><td>Opening & Paul’s Defense</td></tr><tr><td>3:1-5:12</td><td>Paul’s Appeal to the Galatians</td></tr><tr><td>5:13-6:10</td><td>Life in the Spirit</td></tr><tr><td>6:11-18</td><td>Final Warnings</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Ephesians?",
        "answer": "A. Salvation unites us to Christ which changes the way we live.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-3</td><td>Our position in Christ</td></tr><tr><td>4-6</td><td>Our practice in Christ</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Philippians?",
        "answer": "A. How to have joy in Christ regardless of circumstances.<br><br><table><tr><td>1</td><td>Philosophy for Christian Living</td></tr><tr><td>2</td><td>Pattern for Christian Living</td></tr><tr><td>3</td><td>Prize for Christian Living</td></tr><tr><td>4</td><td>Power for Christian Living</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Colossians?",
        "answer": "A. Praising Christ’s person and work, and living out our union with Christ.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-2</td><td>Christ's Person and Work</td></tr><tr><td>3-4</td><td>Union with Christ as basis for Christian living</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of 1 Thessalonians?",
        "answer": "A. An encouragement in Godly living in the face of persecution until Christ returns.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-3</td><td>A Celebration of Faith</td></tr><tr><td>4-5</td><td>A Call to Righteous Living</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of 2 Thessalonians?",
        "answer": "A. Stand firm until the coming of Jesus.<br><br><table><tr><td>1</td><td>Encouragement in Persecution</td></tr><tr><td>2</td><td>Enlightenment about the Coming of the Lord</td></tr><tr><td>3</td><td>Exhortation to Christian Living</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of 1 Timothy?",
        "answer": "A. Lead the church with sound teaching and a godly example.<br><br><table><tr><td>1</td><td>Instruction in Sound Doctrine</td></tr><tr><td>2-3</td><td>Instruction Concerning the Church</td></tr><tr><td>4</td><td>Instruction to Timothy</td></tr><tr><td>5-6</td><td>Instruction Concerning Members of the Church</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of 2 Timothy?",
        "answer": "A. Preach the word and persevere in the faith.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-2</td><td>Commit – Encouragement for Timothy</td></tr><tr><td>3-4</td><td>Contend – Warning of Difficulties Ahead</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Titus?",
        "answer": "A. Pastoral letter about faith and conduct and ministry.<br><br><table><tr><td>1</td><td>Who Should Teach</td></tr><tr><td>2</td><td>What to Teach and How to Live</td></tr><tr><td>3</td><td>What to Do with Factions and False Teachers</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Philemon?",
        "answer": "A. Letter to Philemon to ask him to accept Onesimus as a brother in Christ.<br><br><table><tr><td>1:1-7</td><td>Greeting</td></tr><tr><td>1:8-21</td><td>Plea for Onesimus</td></tr><tr><td>1:22-25</td><td>Closing</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Hebrews?",
        "answer": "A. Christ is superior in every way; don't turn back to old ways.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-2</td><td>Superiority of Christ to prophets and angels</td></tr><tr><td>3-4</td><td>Superiority of Christ to Moses & Joshua</td></tr><tr><td>5-8:5</td><td>Superiority of Christ’s priesthood</td></tr><tr><td>8:6-10:39</td><td>Superiority of New Covenant to Old Covenant</td></tr><tr><td>11-13</td><td>Superiority of faith</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of James?",
        "answer": "A. Live out your faith in action.<br><br><table><tr><td>1-3</td><td>Genuine Faith</td></tr><tr><td>4</td><td>Warnings against Worldliness</td></tr><tr><td>5</td><td>The Return of the Lord</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of 1 Peter?",
        "answer": "A. Remember suffering is temporary and our future inheritance.<br><br><table><tr><td>1</td><td>Present suffering & future inheritance</td></tr><tr><td>2-4:6</td><td>Our suffering in view of Christ’s suffering</td></tr><tr><td>4:7-5:14</td><td>Our suffering in view of Christ’s advent</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of 2 Peter?",
        "answer": "A. Remember Christ and be cautious of false teachers.<br><br><table><tr><td>1</td><td>Grow in Grace and Knowledge</td></tr><tr><td>2</td><td>Beware of False Teachers</td></tr><tr><td>3</td><td>Look for the Lord's Return</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of 1 John?",
        "answer": "A. God is love; walk in His light and love.<br><br><table><tr><td>1</td><td>God is Light</td></tr><tr><td>2-4</td><td>God is Love</td></tr><tr><td>5</td><td>God is Life</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Jude?",
        "answer": "A. Contend for the faith and beware of false teachers.<br><br><table><tr><td>1:1-4</td><td>Greeting</td></tr><tr><td>1:5-16</td><td>Judgment on false teaching</td></tr><tr><td>1:17-23</td><td>Perseverance</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q. Summarize and outline the book of Revelation?",
        "answer": "A. Apocalyptic letter repeating the cycle of God wining and the return of Christ.<br><br><table><tr><td>1</td><td>Prologue</td></tr><tr><td>2-3</td><td>Letters to Seven Churches</td></tr><tr><th colspan=\"2\">7 Recapitulations – Heavenly Visions</th></tr><tr><td>4-7</td><td>Cycle One: Scroll and Seven Seals</td></tr><tr><td>8-11</td><td>Cycle Two: Seven Angels and Seven Trumpets</td></tr><tr><td>12-14</td><td>Cycle Three: Seven symbolic histories</td></tr><tr><td>15-16</td><td>Cycle Four: Seven bowls of God’s wrath</td></tr><tr><td>17-19:10</td><td>Cycle Five: Judgment on Babylon and Vindication of the Church</td></tr><tr><td>19:11-19:21</td><td>Cycle Six: The Final Battle</td></tr><tr><td>20-21:8</td><td>Cycle Seven: The Reign of the Saints and the Last Judgment</td></tr><tr><td>21:9-22:21</td><td>The New Jerusalem and Final Exhortation</td></tr></table>"
    }
]
